Guide to the C. L. R. James papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Writings, 1948-1990s, Undated
  - Subseries II.3: Lectures and Talks, 1958-1991, 2000, Undated
    - Harris, Wilson--A Philosophical Approach, circa 1965 (printed) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Imperialism and Underdeveloped Countries: Who are the Backward Ones?, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Leadership, 1963, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, Undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Mass Movement and Anti-Imperialist Struggle, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - On Nigeria, circa 1966 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Nuclear War and Peace, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Padmore, George, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Pan-Africanism, Reflections on, circa 1969 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - PNM, The Rise and Fall of the Peoples National Movement, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Popular Art and the Cultural Tradition--Translation, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Robeson, Paul, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Seizure of Power, circa 1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Shakespeare, 1963, 1983, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Solidarity, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - West Indians, Notable, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - World Revolution Today, circa 1968-1970s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Wright, Richard, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Untitled:
      - African-American Teachers Association, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Black Alliance, Hackney, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Black Power Conference, First Regional, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Clapham Teachers Centre, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Cricket Society, Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Pan-African Meeting, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Ladbroke Grove--on his 70th Birthday, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - London--Exhibition at Photographers Gallery, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Rutgers University, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - San Francisco, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Tougaloo College, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Trans-Africa Dinner--Freedom Award Ceremony, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Trinidad, Undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Wayne State, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - West Indies, University of--Graduation, 1972 (printed) (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Untitled, Undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Untitled--Transcript incomplete, Undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - By Others:
      - Campbell, Frank--"In Celebration of the October Revolution", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Rodney, Walter--"Marx in the Liberation of Africa", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Subseries II.4: Interviews, circa 1970s-1996, Undated
    The material here consists for the most part of transcripts of interviews given by James on a variety of topics and to a variety of individuals from professional journalists to budding scholars. Some of the interviews have been published.
    - Topic:
      - America, Visit to and Politics, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - British Trotskyism, 1986 (Printed) (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Black Jacobins, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Cricket, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Lamming, George, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Literary Life, Making of, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Manley, Norman, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Marxism and Black Nationalists, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Minty Alley, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Padmore, George, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Pan African Congress, Focus on the Sixth, Undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Race in Great Britain, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Robeson, Paul, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Toussaint L'Ouverture, circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Trotsky, Leon--interviewed by C L R James--1934--Transcript, Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Women, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Interviewer:
      - Hall, Stuart, Undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Haut, Woody, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Hillegas, Jan, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Nevin, Charles, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Peiris, Denzil, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Ramchand, Ken, 1980, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Sunitha, K. T., circa 1983 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Thompson, E. P.--Talking History, circa 1980 (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Warhaftig, Alan, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Regarding James
      - Grimshaw, Anna, A Conversation with, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Hill, Robert and Jim Murray, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Rawick, George, A Conversation with, Undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Subseries II.5: Writings by Others--Drafts and Manuscripts, 1969-1990s, Undated
    Many, although not all, of the drafts and manuscripts here were received by James in the 1970s during his teaching period in the United States. A student paper on Walt Whitman by Nettie Kravitz, one of James associates from Detroit, is here as is a piece on revolutionary leadership by the Boggs. Also here is a film script of James' novel, Minty Alley.
    - General, Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Boggs, James and Grace, "The Awesome Responsibilities of Revolutionary Leadership", 1970 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Kravitz, Nettie, "Walt Whitman: Bard of the Open Road," 1962 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Lovelace, Earl-- The Dragon Can't Dance, Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Marshall, William-- Christophe: King of Haiti, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ramchand, Kenneth, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Robinson, Cedric, 1976, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 7 to 8)
    - Samoiloff, Louise Cripps-- C L R James: Memories and Commentaries--Manuscript, circa 1990s (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 9 to 10)
    - Samoiloff, Louise Cripps-- Lirazel: An English Love Story of a White Woman and a Black Man--Manuscript, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Turner, Terisa, 1976-1978 (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Warhaftig, Alan, 1978, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Warhaftig, Alan-- Minty Alley--Screen Play, 1993, 1997 (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 15 to 16)
    - "The Development of Children's Literature", Undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "The Problem: Folksong and Social Action", Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - "Socio Cultural and Philosophical Bases of James' Vision", circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "Towards New Structures, Methods and Procedures in Accordance with the Aims of the 31st December Revolution", circa 1982 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Untitled Manuscript, Undated (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 21 to 22)
- Series III: Publishing--Johnson-Forest through Facing Reality, 1943-1972, Undated
  Correspondence, reports, drafts and articles, pamphlets, and publications created by members of the Correspondence Publishing Committee and the Facing Reality Group are included in this series. Writings, especially for Correspondence and Speak Out cover popular culture as well as political and social issues of the day.
  - Subseries III.1: General, 1946-1972
    Although the correspondence here pertains largely to the writing and editing of publications for the Correspondence Publishing Committee and the Facing Reality Group, it also reveals some of the fault lines that led to the ruptures within the groups. Also in this subseries are editors' reports, and drafts and notes for articles; among the articles and drafts are typescripts of bulletins written in the mid-1950s by James.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1954-1958, 1961-1963 (6 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 23 to 28)
      - James, C.L.R.--Outgoing, 1953-1961, Undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Bernard, Claude (Raoul), 1954-1956 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Boggs, Grace Lee, 1954-1962, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Boggs, James--editor, 1960-1964, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Castoriades, Cornelius (Chalieu or Cardan)1956 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Membership, To the, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - General, 1946-1956, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Articles and Drafts
      - Circa 1950s (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Bulletins, List of by James, Undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Bulletins--1955-1956 (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Caucus and Convention Material, 1947, 1957, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Convention--Address by C.L.R James--Transcript, 1951-1952 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Editor's Reports, 1955, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Facing Reality
      - Drafts, Circa 1960s (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 15 to 16)
      - Abolition, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Afro-Americans, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Cuba, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Gathering Forces, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Meetings--Notes 1967 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Format and Manuals, Undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Publications, Report and Discussion, Undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "Record, For The--The Johnson-Forest Tendency", 1972 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Reprints--Articles by J R Johnson, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Weaver, Report by, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Subseries III. 2: Printed Material, 1943-1969, Undated
    Although there is not a full run of either Correspondence or Speak Out here, many issues of each publication are included in this subseries. Also here are bulletins and pamphlets created by or associated with the members of Correspondence and Facing Reality. Most of the materials are mimeographed publications; the bulk of the material in this subseries was created by the Correspondence Publishing Committee.
    - Correspondence
      - 1951 Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 27)
      - 1952 Jan-1953 Jun, (5 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 28 to 32)
      - Special Subscription, circa 1953 (Box 15, Folder 33)
      - 1956-1959 (5 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 34 to 38)
      - 1960-1961, 1964 (4 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Private Letters, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - News and Letters, 1961 Sept-Nov (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Speak Out, 1964-1969 (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "America, Post-War, and Bolshevism"--by J R Johnson, Circa 1945-1946 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "American Bolshevik Party, Task of Building--Education, Propaganda and Agitation"--by J R Johnson, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "American Question, Resolution of"--by J R Johnson, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Balance Sheet--"Trotskyism in the United States, 1940-1947"-- published by the Johnson-Forest Tendency, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - The Balance Sheet Completed-- " Ten Years of American Trotskyism", 1951 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Black Studies and the Contemporary Student, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Black Struggle, Basic Documents on, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Bulletins
      - Discussion, 1950 Sept-Oct (2 Folders) includes --"State Capitalism and the World Revolution"--by Johnson-Forest--published by the Socialist Workers Party, 1950 Sep (Box 17, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Internal, 1947 Jul (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Internal, 1947 Aug-Sept, Undated (5 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 4 to 8)
      - International Situation--Yugoslavia, 1949 Dec-1950 Jan (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Statement by R. S. C. on W. Va., circa 1951 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Statement of the Secretariat, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Trotsky, Leon on the Labor Party--1932-1938 1948 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Of the Workers' Party, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Worker's Paper, The Need for, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - "Detroit: The July Days, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "Eastern Europe, the Revolution in"--A Discussion on, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "Fourth International and the World Socialist Revolution: Resolution", 1946 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "French Social History", Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - [Hegelian Logic, Notes on]--Edited, Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Hegel's Science of Logic, Lenin on"-- Raya Dunayevskaya, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - [Hungarian Revolution], circa 1956 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Marx, Karl, Three Essays by--Introduction by J R Johnson, F Forest and Ria Stone, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Marx's Capital, Outline of--Volume 1-- Lectures by Forest--published by Workers Party, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Mistaken Identity, A Case of"--Martin Harvey, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "The Mode of Production and its Agents", Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Organization, Letters on--J R Johnson to Martin Glaberman, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Organization, Letters on--J R Johnson to Martin Glaberman--Notes and Addendum, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Party Crisis, The Roots of"--by J R Johnson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Perspectives and Proposals--by C L R James, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Russian Question--Resolutions of the 1941 Convention on the Character of the Russian State, circa 1940s (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Russian Question, World Revolutionary Perspectives and--by F Forest and J R Johnson, 1947 (Includes a photocopy of extensive hand-written comments by James) (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Southern Local, History of--Circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - State Capitalism and World Revolution--by C L R James, circa 1956 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - What We Must Not Do, circa 1956 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - The Woman Question, Panel Discussion, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Workers Organization, Towards a, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Untitled, circa 1960s (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Printed Material, 1933-1992, Undated
  Contained here are many pamphlets, clippings, and a few assorted materials by C.L.R. James and others. Material from the Johnson-Forest Tendency period as well as material that pre-dates or follows that period is included.
  - Subseries IV.1: Pamphlets, 1933-1992, Undated
    The pamphlets in this subseries include James' first publication in Britain, "The Case for West Indian Government" (Hogarth Press, 1933) through his last, "Walter Rodney and the Question of Power" (Race Today Publications, 1983), and many of his writings, covering his varied interests, in between. Also here is "Down with Starvation Wages," which James helped striking share-croppers of South-East Missouri create during the Second World War.
    The pamphlets produced by others include much literature of the radical left; these are arranged by writer or by topic.
    - By James
      - Dialectic and History, An Introduction, Undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Down with Starvation Wages in South-East Missouri, Circa 1941 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - From DuBois to Fanon, Undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Every Cook Can Govern, 1956, 1966, 1986, 1992 (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 11 to 12)
      - Facing Reality, 1958 (with Grace Lee and Pierre Chalieu) (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - "Fanon and the Caribbean" in International Tribute to Frantz Fanon, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Federation: 'We Failed Miserably', 1959 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - The Invading Socialist Society, 1947, 1972 (with Forest and Ria Stone) (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Lenin, Trotsky and the Vanguard Party, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Marxism and Intellectuals, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Why Negroes Should Oppose the War, circa 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Nkrumah, Kwame and the West Indies, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - PNM! Go Forward--A Critique of PNM's Internal Party Politics, Section I--by C L R James, 1958-1960 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Rodney, Walter and the Question of Power, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - State Capitalism and World Revolution--3rd Edition, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - "Supplement" in Not For Sale--by Michael Manley, circa 1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - West Indian Government, the Case for, 1933, 1967 (Hogarth Press) (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - "West Indians of East Indian Descent"--and Response by H.P. Singh, circa 1960s (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - By Others
      - General, 1971-1979 circa 1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Advocators--Publisher, 1974-1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Africa, 1964, 1975, 1976, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Boggs, Grace--Speeches, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Breitman, George, Editor--"Leon Trotsky on Black Nationalism, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Caribbean, circa 1960s, 1975, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Castoriades, Cornelius, 1984, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Dunayevskaya, Raya, 1977-1989 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Eastman, Max--"Last Stand of Dialectic Materialism", circa 1934 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Glaberman, Martin, 1952, 1964-1975, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Gough, Kathleen, 1961-1962 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Great Britain, 1982, 1984, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Guérin, Daniel--"Cuba-Paris", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Guérin, Daniel-- Negroes on the March, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Poetry, 1981-1983 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Race Today Collective--Publisher, 1974-1975, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Romano, Paul and Ria Stone, "The American Worker", 1947, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Turner, Terisa E., 1985, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - United States, 1974-1977, 1987, 1990, Undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Webb, Constance--on Richard Wright, circa 1940s, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Women, 1970, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Williams, Eric--Addresses, 1973, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Workers and Farmers Party--Election Manifesto, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.2: General, 1940-1980s
    This small subseries holds announcements of lectures and events, many of which featured James; printed articles by James; and a few articles and writings annotated by James; and clippings of articles by or about James.
    - Announcements--of Lectures and Events, 1940 1950s-1980s (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Articles by James, circa 1960s-1980s (2 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Articles and Writings--Annotated by James, circa 1960s-1980s (3 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Clippings, 1960s-1970s, Undated (4 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 11 to 14)
    - Clippings--The Keys (1930s)--Transcripts, circa 1980s (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Series V: Teaching, circa 1970-1981
  Student papers, graded by James, comprise the bulk of this series, but also here are course outlines for courses taught by James and others, and a Federal City College yearbook dedicated to James.
  - African Studies, Institute of Sierra Leone, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Black Studies, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Course Outlines--General, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Course Outlines and Materials--Acklyn Lynch, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - District of Columbia, University of, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Federal City College--Profile, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Federal City College--Yearbook, 1973 (Dedicated to C.L.R. James) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Student Papers--Graded, 1975-1981, (8 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 8 to 15)
    [Restricted until 2060]
- Series VI: Subject Files, 1952-1992
  This series contains writings and printed material about James and various subjects as well as a few personal materials. Some of the printed material contained here has been annotated by James.
  - Subseries VI.1: About C.L.R. James, 1966-1992
    Tributes to, and writings about, James comprise this subseries.
    - Researching James, circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Writings--General, 1984-1993, Undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Grimshaw, Anna--On C.L.R. James, 1991 (4 Pamphlets) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Legacy of, in Against the Currents, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Journal, CLR James, 1991, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Radical America--Special Issue, 1970 May (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Sancho, T. Anson--"CLR The Man and His Work", Undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Tributes
      - General, 1972-1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Addresses and Lectures, 1989-1990s (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Birthday--65th, 1966 (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Institute--Proposal, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Oakland University--Honorary Degree, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA)--Celebration of Life, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - University of West Indies--Symposium, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - University of West Indies--Tribute to a Scholar, circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Urgent Tasks, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - WBAI Memorial, Circa 1990 (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Wellesley College--Conference, 1991-1992 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Subseries VI.2: Personal, 1952-1989
    Some material in this series dates from James' time at Federal City College in the 1970s and is related to his employment and finances. Drafts of his will, obituaries and information regarding his funeral are also here. Legal briefs from James' struggles with the United States Immigration and Naturalization Service, and redacted photocopies of the FBI files on James and the Johnson-Forest Tendency are also here.
    - General, Circa 1970s (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Death--Funeral, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Death--Obituaries, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Ephemera, circa 1970s (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Federal City College--Employment, 1969-1977 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Financial
      - Banking and Income, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 24)
      - Bills and receipts, circa 1970s (Box 24, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 24, Folder 26)
      - Contracts, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 27)
      - Taxes, 1977-1979 (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - Will--Olive James (sister), 1977 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Notes and Addresses, circa 1970s (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Will--Drafts, circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Legal
      - Immigration--Legal Briefs, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 32)
      - FBI Files--James--Redacted Photocopies, circa 1950s (3 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 33 to 35)
      - FBI Files, Johnson-Forest-- Redacted Photocopies, circa 1950s (2 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 36 to 37)
  - Subseries VI.3: General, 1957-1986
    Conference materials, and printed material regarding Caribbean and Africa countries primarily, comprise the bulk of this subseries.
    - Africa, 1976-1978, Undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - African Elected Member's Organisation, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Black Manifesto, The Church's Response to, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Boggs, James, circa 1993 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Bookfair of Third World Radicals, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Caribbean, circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Caribbean--Frome Monymusk Land Company, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Caribbean--Papers by others,1974 Undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Confererences:
      - 1970-1980 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Black National, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Black Power--1st Regional, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Caribbean Historians, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Caribbean Unity, 1967, 1972-1974, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Pan-African Conferences, circa 1970s, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Texas, University of--Austin, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Ghana, 1980, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Guyana, 1975-1976, undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Henry's Citadelle--Paper, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Howard University,1977 Undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - James, Selma, 1972-1994, Undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Lamming, George, 1972, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Manley, Michael, Undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - New Beginning Movement, 1974, Undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Nigeria--Draft Constitution, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Oilfield Workers Trade Union, 1973, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Puerto Rico, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Papua New Guniea, circa 1970s (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Race Today Collective--Carnival, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Quebec--Manifesto, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - South Africa, 1977-1979 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Tanzania, 1968, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Third World Book Review, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Trinidad and Tobago--Constitution, 1962, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 33)